Privacy Policy – Visitors of AIRe Link Website

Dated 15 March 2021

Version 1.0

With the following information we would like to inform you about the processing of your personal data

by us and your rights resulting from the data protection laws and especially from the general data

protection regulation (regulation (EU) 2016/679 - "GDPR").

Table of contents

1 Controller and data protection officer .......................................................................... 3

2 What are my rights as a data subject? .......................................................................... 4

3 General information regarding the topic „purposes“ .................................................... 7

4 General information regarding the topic „legal bases“ ................................................. 7

4.1 Legal bases for the processing of personal data .......................................................... 7

5 General information regarding the topic „obligation to preserve records and time limits

of erasure“ ................................................................................................................. 10

6 General information regarding the topic „disclosure of personal data“ ...................... 10

7 Cookies ..................................................................................................................... 11

7.1 General information regarding the topic „cookies“ ..................................................... 11

8 Central administration tool – Google Tag Manager .................................................... 12

9 In the context of which processing activities are my personal data processed?.......... 12

9.1 Processing activity – visiting of our website ............................................................... 12

9.2 Processing activity - Content-Management-System .................................................. 13

9.3 Processing activity – Consent Management Platform ................................................. 14

9.4 Processing activity – Special fonts / Google fonts ...................................................... 15

9.5 Processing activity – Webanalytics.............................................................................. 16

9.5.1 Google Analytics ........................................................................................................ 16

9.6 Processing activity – Social networks on our website ................................................. 17

9.6.1 Online presence in social networks ............................................................................ 17

9.6.2 Possibilities of objection in social networks ............................................................... 18

9.7 Processing activity – Targeting und Advertisement .................................................... 18

9.7.1 Google Adwords ........................................................................................................ 18

9.7.2 LinkedIn Insight Tag .................................................................................................. 19

2

9.7.3 MailChimp.................................................................................................................. 20

9.7.4 Newsletter.................................................................................................................. 21

9.8 Processing activity – Youtube ..................................................................................... 22

9.9 Processing activity - Cloudfront................................................................................. 23

10 Konica Minolta Global Policy ...................................................................................... 23

3

1 Controller and data protection officer

Controller in accordance with Art. 4 (7) GDPR is:

Konica Minolta Business Solutions Europe GmbH

Europaallee 17, 30855 Langenhagen

Tel.: +49 (0)511 7404-0

Email: info@konicaminolta.eu

(See our Imprint)

If you have any questions concerning data protection, you are welcome to contact our company

data protection officer:

Dr. Frederike Rehker

Konica Minolta Business Solutions Europe GmbH

Europaallee 17, 30855 Langenhagen

Tel.: +49 (0)511 7404-0

Email: dataprotection@konicaminolta.eu

4

2 What are my rights as a data subject?

As a data subject, you have the following rights:

2.1 Right of access (Art. 15 GDPR): You have the right to be informed at any time of the categories

of personal data processed, the purposes of processing, any recipients or categories of recipients

of your personal data and the planned storage period.

2.2 Right of rectification (Art. 16 GDPR): You have the right to request the rectification or

completion of personal data concerning you that is incorrect or incomplete.

2.3 Right to erasure („right to be forgotten“) (Art. 17 GDPR): You have the right to request the

immediate erasure of your personal data. In particular, we are obliged as the responsible party

to delete your data in the following cases:

− Your personal data is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected.

− A processing of your personal data took place solely on the basis of your consent, which

you have now withdrawn, and there is no other legal basis that legitimises a processing

of your personal data.

− You have objected to a processing which is based on the legitimate or public interest

and we cannot prove that there are legitimate grounds for processing.

− Your personal data has been processed unlawfully.

− The erasure of your personal data is necessary in order to comply with a legal obligation

to which we are subject.

− Your personal data has been collected in connection with information society services

offered in accordance with Art. 8 I GDPR.

− Please be aware that the right to erasure is subject to a limitation in the following cases,

so that a deletion is excluded:

− Your personal data is used to exercise the right to freedom of expression and

information.

− Your personal data serves to fulfil a legal obligation to which we are subject.

− Your personal data is used to carry out a task that is in the public interest or in the

exercise of official authority that has been assigned to us.

− Your personal data serves the public interest in the field of public health.

− Your personal data are necessary for archiving purposes in the public interest, for

scientific or historical research or for statistical purposes.

− Your personal data serve for us to establishment, exercise or defend legal claims.

5

2.4 Right of restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR): You also have the right to request that the

processing of your personal data be restricted; in such a case, your personal data will be

excluded from any processing. This right applies if:

− You contest the accuracy of your personal data and we have to verify the accuracy of

your personal data.

− The processing of your personal data is unlawful and instead of erasing your personal

data, you request a restriction of processing.

− We no longer need your personal data for the fulfilment of the specific purposes, but

you still need this personal data to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.

− You object to the processing of your personal data and it has not yet been determined

whether your or our legitimate reasons override this.

2.5 Right of data portability (Art. 20 GDPR): You have the right to receive the personal data

concerning you that you have provided to us as a controller in a structured, common and

machine-readable format and to transfer it to another controller. Furthermore, you also have the

right to request that your personal data be transferred from us to another controller, insofar as

this is technically feasible.

The requirements for the applicability of data portability are:

− Your personal data is automatically processed based on your consent or a contract.

− Your personal data does not serve to fulfil a legal obligation to which we are subject.

− Your personal data will not be used to perform a task that is in the public interest.

− Your personal data do not serve for the performance of a task which is performed in

the exercise of a official authority delegated to us.

− The exercise of your right shall not interfere with the rights and freedoms of others.

2.6 Right to object (Art. 21 GDPR): You have the right at any time to object to the processing of

your personal data on grounds arising from your particular situation. This also applies to

profiling. The requirement for this is that the processing is based on a legitimate interest on our

part (Art. 6 I 1 lit. f GDPR) or the public interest (Art. 6 I 1 lit. e GDPR).

Furthermore, you may also at any time object to the processing of your personal data for the

purposes of direct marketing or profiling linked to such direct marketing.

Should you object to the processing of your personal data based on a legitimate interest, we will

check in each individual case whether we can show grounds worthy of protection that override

your interests and rights and freedoms. In the event that there are no reasons worthy of

protection on our part or your interests as well as rights and freedoms override our own, your

personal data will no longer be processed.

6

An exception is made if your personal data is still used for the establishment, exercise or defence

of legal claims. If you object to the processing of your personal data for the purposes of direct

marketing or profiling, insofar as this is linked to such direct marketing, your personal data will

no longer be processed for these purposes.

2.7 Right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR): Right to lodge a

complaint with the supervisory authority (Art. 77 DPA): You also have the right to lodge a

complaint with a supervisory authority at any time, in particular with a supervisory authority in

the Member State of your residence, place of work or place of suspected infringement, if you

consider that the processing of personal data concerning you is in breach of the data protection

regulations.

The address of the supervisory authority responsible for our company is:

Barbara Thiel

Die Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz Niedersachsen

Prinzenstraße 5

30159 Hannover

Telefon +49 (0) 511-120 4500

Fax +49 (0) 511-120 4599

poststelle@lfd.niedersachsen.de

2.8 Right of withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR): If you have given us consent to process your personal

data, you can withdraw this consent at any time without giving reasons and in an informal

manner. Withdrawal of consent does not affect the lawfulness of the processing that has taken

place on the basis of the consent up to the section of withdrawal.

7

3 General information regarding the topic „purposes“

As a matter of principle, the processing of your personal data by us is always linked to a

specified, explicit and legitimate purpose, which has already been defined before the processing

activity is commenced, in accordance with the principle of purpose limitation under Art. 5 I lit. b

GDPR. In the further course of this privacy policy, when a processing activity is cited, a

description of the specific purpose is also included.

4 General information regarding the topic „legal bases“

We process your personal data in accordance with the GDPR. Accordingly, the processing of your

personal data is always founded on a legal basis. Article 6 of the GDPR defines legal bases for

the processing of personal data.

4.1 Legal bases for the processing of personal data

Consent

If we obtain your consent for the processing of your personal data, the processing will be carried

out on the legal basis of Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR. The following example serves to clarify this legal

basis: You receive advertising from us by electronic mail and/or telephone and have given your

prior consent.

Contract or pre-contractual measure

If the processing of your personal data is necessary for the fulfilment of a contract with you or

for the implementation of pre-contractual measures taken in response to your request, the legal

basis on which our processing is based is Art. 6 I 1 lit. b GDPR.

Legal obligation

In cases where the processing of your personal data is necessary to comply with a legal obligation

to which we are subject, this processing is based on Art. 6 I 1 lit. c GDPR.

Vital interest

Should the processing of your personal data be necessary to protect your vital interests or those

of another person, this processing is carried out in accordance with Art. 6 I 1 lit. d GDPR.

Public interest

In cases where we process your personal data in order to perform a task which is in the public

interest or in the exercise of official authority delegated to us, Art. 6 I 1 lit. e GDPR constitutes

the legal basis.

8

Legitimate interest

If the processing of personal data is necessary to safeguard a legitimate interest of our company

or a third party and at the same time the interests, basic rights and fundamental freedoms of

the data subject, which require the protection of personal data, do not override our legitimate

interest, Art. 6 I 1 lit. f GDPR serves as the legal basis for the processing.

Legal bases for the processing of special categories of personal data

If, in extraordinary cases, we need to process special categories of personal data, such as

− data on racial or ethnic origin (e.g. skin color or special languages),

− data on political opinions (e.g. party memberships),

− data on religious or philosophical beliefs (e.g. membership of a sect),

− data on trade union membership,

− genetic data,

− biometric data (e.g. fingerprints or photographs),

− health data (e.g. identification numbers for disabilities),

− or data concerning the sex life or sexual orientation

by you, this processing is based on one of the following legal bases, which are de-fined in Article

9 GDPR:

Explicit consent

If you have given us your explicit consent for the processing of the above categories of personal

data, this constitutes the legal basis for the processing in accordance with Art. 9 II lit. a GDPR.

Performing duties under social security/protection and employment law

If the processing of special categories of personal data relating to you is necessary in order to

comply with a legal obligation arising from social security/protection or employment law, the

legal basis for this processing is Art. 9 II lit. b GDPR.

Protection of vital interests

If the processing of special categories of personal data relating to you should be necessary to

protect your vital interests or those of another person, such processing is carried out pursuant

to Art. 9 II lit. c GDPR.

Manifestly public data

Insofar as special categories of personal data of yours are processed, which have previously been

made public by yourself, the processing of these data is based on Art. 9 II lit. e GDPR.

9

Establishment / Exercise / Defence of legal claims

Insofar as the processing of the special categories of personal data relating to you serves us to

establish, exercise or defend legal claims, Art. 9 II lit. f GDPR constitutes the legal basis for the

processing.

Substantial public interest

In the case of the processing of special categories of personal data concerning you in order to

safeguard a substantial public interest arising from EU or national law, the processing is based

on Art. 9 II lit. g GDPR.

Assessment of the person's work capacity or other medical purposes such as health care

If the processing of special categories of personal data relating to you arises from a law of the

EU or a Member State or a contract concluded with a member of a health profession and is carried

out for the purposes of preventive health care, occupational medicine, assessment of an

employee's work capacity, medical diagnosis, care or treatment in the health or social field or

the management of systems and services in the health or social field, this processing is based

on Art. 9 II lit. h GDPR.

Public interest in the area of public health

If the processing of special categories of personal data of yours should be necessary for public

health reasons, including protection against cross-border health threats such as pandemics, this

processing is carried out on the legal basis of Article 9 II lit. i GDPR.

Archival purposes, scientific / historical research purposes, statistical purposes

Should the processing of special categories of personal data relating to you arise from a right of

the EU or a member state, which stipulates processing for archiving, scientific or historical

research or statistical purposes in the public interest, this processing is based on Art. 9 II

lit. j GDPR.

10

5 General information regarding the topic „obligation to preserve

records and time limits of erasure“

Unless otherwise stated, we delete personal data in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR or restrict its

processing in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR. Apart from the retention periods stated in this

privacy policy, we process and store your personal data only as long as they are necessary for

the fulfilment of our contractual and legal obligations. Personal data that is no longer required

after the purpose has been fulfilled will be regularly deleted, unless further processing is

required for a limited period of time, which may result from other legally permissible purposes.

In order to fulfil documentation obligations as well as to comply with statutory obligations to

preserve records in Germany, the necessary documents are kept for six years in accordance with

§ 257 I Commercial Code (HGB) and for ten years in accordance with § 147 I of the Fiscal Code

of Germany (AO).

6 General information regarding the topic „disclosure of

personal data“

Recipient of your data

We do not sell or rent user data in principle. A transfer to third parties beyond the scope

described in this privacy policy will only take place if this is necessary for the processing of the

respective requested service. For this purpose, we work together with service providers in the

areas of marketing, sales, IT, logistics and human resources, among others. We select these

service providers extremely carefully. In other cases we transfer data to requesting governmental

authorities. However, this only takes place if there is a legal obligation to do so, for example if

a court order exists.

Locations of the processing of your personal data

In principle, we process your data in Germany and in other European countries (EU/EEA). If your

data is processed in countries outside the European Union (i.e. in so-called third countries), this

will only take place if you have expressly consented to it, if it is stipulated by law or if it is

necessary for our service provision to you. If, in these exceptional cases, we process data in third

countries, this will be done by ensuring that certain measures are taken (i.e. on the basis of an

adequacy decision by the EU Commission or by presenting suitable guarantees in accordance

with Art. 44ff. GDPR).

11

7 Cookies

7.1 General information regarding the topic „cookies“

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard drive in

accordance with the browser you are using and through which certain information flows to the

site that sets the cookie. Many of the cookies we use are deleted after the browser session ends

(so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain on your end device and enable us to recognize

your browser on your next visit (persistent cookies).

Cookies are used on our website for various purposes. For a better overview, each cookie has

been assigned to one of the following categories:

Necessary

Cookies that belong to this category are required to ensure the core functionality of this website.

Necessary cookies help make a website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation

and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these

cookies. Legal basis: Art. 6 I 1 lit. f GDPR

Preferences

Preference cookies enable a website to remember information that changes the way the website

behaves or looks, like your preferred language or the region that you are in. Legal basis: Art. 6 I

1 lit. a GDPR

Statistics

Statistic cookies help website owners to understand how visitors interact with websites by

collecting and reporting information anonymously. Legal basis: Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR

Marketing

Marketing cookies are used to track visitors across websites. The intention is to display ads that

are relevant and engaging for the individual user and thereby more valuable for publishers and

third party advertisers. Legal basis: Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR

In the settings of the browser you use, you have the option of rejecting the acceptance of cookies

or, for example, to limit this rejection to cookies from other parties, so-called third-party

cookies. However, the browser settings you have made may mean that you may not be able to

use all the functions of our website to their full extent.

Here you will find further information on the administration of cookies for corresponding

browsers:

Internet Explorer: How to delete cookie files in Internet Explorer (microsoft.com)

Google Chrome: Clear, enable, and manage cookies in Chrome - Computer - Google Chrome

Help

Firefox: Delete browsing, search and download history on Firefox | Firefox Help (mozilla.org)

12

8 Central administration tool – Google Tag Manager

On our website we use the Google Tag Manager, by the Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway,

Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. With the help of the Tag Manager, we can integrate and manage

any software solution, such as Google Analytics, centrally on our website via corresponding code

sections - also called tags. These code sections also serve to collect data about your browser,

your website visits or to set cookies. However, the Google Tag Manager is only a domain that

neither sets cookies nor processes personal data. A processing of your personal data takes place

exclusively through the solutions integrated via the code sections, such as Google Analytics

itself.

Further information on the processing of your personal data within the framework of the

individual solutions used can be found in the separate sections of the individual solutions in the

following.

9 In the context of which processing activities are my personal data

processed?

9.1 Processing activity – visiting of our website

If you use our website for purely informative purposes, i.e. if you do not register or provide us

with information in any other way, we only collect the personal data that your personal browser

sends to our server. This data is technically necessary for the display of the website. Furthermore,

this data is technically necessary to ensure the stability and security of our website. The legal

basis for the processing of your personal data is in this case Art. 6 I 1 lit. f GDPR; the legitimate

interest in this case is the provision and optimal presentation of this website as well as the

protection of this website from external attacks and their follow-up. We delete these personal

data after the end of the usage process, unless we need them for the purposes of misuse

detection and misuse prosecution; in such a case, we retain these data for a maximum of 30

days.

13

When you visit our website, the following personal data may therefore be processed, which is

automatically transmitted from your browser to our servers and stored there in the form of so-

called "log files":

− IP address of the end-device used to access the website

− Date, time and duration of the request

− Country of origin of the request

− Content of the request (concrete page / file)

− Access status/http status code (e.g. "200 OK")

− Internet address of the website from which the request to access our website was made

− Browser

− Operating system and user interface

− Language and version of the browser software

− Amount of data transmitted in each case

− Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)

9.2 Processing activity - Content-Management-System

For our website we use the Content-Management-System (short: CMS) called WordPress.

WordPress is as an Open Source CMS provided by the company WordPress Foundation. The CMS

is used to present and manage our website and enables us to create website content. In the

course of using the CMS, we collect activity data from all visitors of our website in the way

described under “9.1. Processing activity – visiting our website”. Wordpress does not track our

visitors or set cookies.

In principle, data is stored directly in the WordPress data base, so that any data collected by

WordPress is stored on the designated web servers of SiteGround in Spain. SiteGround Spain S.L.

is a webhosting company that provides Wordpress instances.

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the scope of the visitor activities

collected within the scope of the use of WordPress is our legitimate interest pursuant to Art. 6 I

1 lit. f GDPR. Our legitimate interest here is to ensure the operation of our website.

14

9.3 Processing activity – Consent Management Platform

On our website we use the Cookiebot Consent Management Plattform. This is a consent

management tool based on JavaScript. With the help of this tool, we can give the visitor of our

website both an overview of the essential software solutions used and the possibility to decide

on the use of any other software solutions that require prior consent. Furthermore, with the help

of the platform, we can meet the requirement resulting from the GDPR for consent management,

which provides, among other things, the possibility to prove that consents have been given or

not.

In the context of the use of the Cookiebot Consent Management Platform, the following data

may be processed:

− Consent data

− Consent -ID

− Consent status (Opt-in, Opt-out)

− Consent timestamp

− Version of the banner template

− Device data (http Agent, http Referrer)

− Anonymous IP Address

− Country via IP Address

The use of the Cookiebot Consent Management Platform and the associated processing of

personal data serves to fulfill legal obligations within the meaning of Art. 6 I 1 lit. c GDPR. Thus,

the use of the platform is necessary both to comply with the obligation to provide documentary

evidence within the meaning of Art. 5 II GDPR and the legal obligation resulting from the

judgment "ECLI:EU:C:2019:801" of the European Court of Justice and the related judgment "I ZR

7/16" of the German Federal Court of Justice, according to which § 15 III 1 of the German

Telemedia Act (TMG) is to be interpreted with regard to Art. 5 III 1 of Directive 2020/58/EC in

such a way that the service provider may only use cookies to create usage profiles for the

purposes of advertising or market research with the consent of the user.

Deletion of your personal data in connection with the use of the Cookie Consent Management

Platform will take place as soon as it is no longer required to fulfill the purpose. In case of

withdrawal of consent, we retain the information regarding the withdrawal for three years. The

retention results on the one hand from the accountability according to Art. 5 II GDPR and on the

other hand from the regular statute of limitations according to § 195 German Civil Code (BGB).

The period of this limitation begins according to § 199 BGB with the end of the year in which the

claim arose. Thus, the statute of limitations begins at the end of December 31 of the year in

which the withdrawal occurred and ends three years later on December 31 at 00:00.

15

9.4 Processing activity – Special fonts / Google fonts

On our website, we use fonts from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA

94043, USA. These fonts are grouped together by Google under the name Google Fonts. By using

Google Fonts, no cookies are set on your device. The fonts are loaded and integrated via the

corresponding application programming interfaces (APIs for short) from Google

(fonts.googleapis.com and fonts.gstatic.com). The request to load and integrate the Google

Fonts takes place shortly after your visit to our website. The request transmits personal data

such as your IP address or the version of your browser to the Google servers and requests the

corresponding cascading style sheets (CSS files) and font files from Google. Style sheets are files

that are used to change the design of a website, such as the font or font size. A font file contains

any information about how the font is displayed. Requests for CSS files are stored by Google for

one day and requests for font files are stored for one year.

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the context of the use of Google Fonts

is your consent pursuant to Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR.

Due to Google's localization, the transfer of your personal data to Google may involve a third

country transfer, i.e. a transfer of personal data to a destination that is neither in the European

Union nor in the European Economic Area, in this case especially to the USA.

The processing of your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according

to Art. 49 I lit. a GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in

place. As a result, the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights

and freedoms of data subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to

be exercised. Information on your right of withdrawal can be found under section 2.8 "Right of

withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR)" in this privacy policy.

Your personal data will not be stored by us as the controller.

16

9.5 Processing activity – Webanalytics

9.5.1 Google Analytics

On our website we use the service Google Analytics. This is a web analytics service provided by

the Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (hereinafter: Google).

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website and to improve it regularly. We can

use the statistics obtained to improve our offer and make it more interesting for you as a user.

Within the scope of the use of Google Analytics, cookies are set on your end device which enable

an analysis of your visit / use of our website. You can find further information on the topic of

cookies under "7. cookies". You can prevent the storage of cookies by making the appropriate

setting in your browser; however, we would like to inform you that you may then not be able to

use all functions of this website to their full extent. In addition, you can prevent the collection

of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address)

and the further processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser

plugin available under the following link (https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

When the information stored in the cookies about your visit and use of our website is transferred

to Google's servers, it may be transferred to a third country (e.g. to the USA) due to its

localization. However, due to the activated anonymization function, your IP address will be

shortened within the European Union or the European Economic Area even before it is transferred

to Google. Furthermore, the IP address transmitted by your browser will not be merged with

other Google data.

On behalf of the provider of this website, Google will use the information received to evaluate

your use of the website, to compile reports regarding the website activities and to provide further

services to the website provider in connection with the use of the website and the internet. The

legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the context of the use of Google Analytics

is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR.

Due to Google's localization, the transfer of your personal data to Google may involve a third

country transfer, i.e. a transfer of personal data to a destination that is neither in the European

Union nor in the European Economic Area, in this case especially to the USA. The processing of

your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according to Art. 49 I lit. a

GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in place. As a result,

the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights and freedoms of data

subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to be exercised.

Information on your right of withdrawal can be found under section 2.8 "Right of withdrawal (Art.

7 GDPR)" in this privacy policy. You can find more information on the terms of use and data

protection of Google Analytics under or Safeguarding your data - Analytics Help (google.com)

17

9.6 Processing activity – Social networks on our website

9.6.1 Online presence in social networks

Within social networks, we, as the provider of the website, use the offers of online platforms to

inform active users about information offers and services from Konica Minolta and, if interested,

to communicate directly via the platforms. The social media channels thus complement our own

website presence and offer interested parties who prefer this type of information an alternative

means of communication. We are currently represented in the following networks with our own

online profiles:

LinkedIn: AIRe Link Remote Visual Support | LinkedIn

Youtube:AIRe Link - YouTube

As soon as you access the respective Konica Minolta profiles on the corresponding social network

in your network, the terms and conditions and data processing guidelines of the respective

providers apply. We have no influence on the data collection and its further use by the social

networks. Thus, we only know that your data will be processed for market research and

advertising purposes and that usage profiles will be created from your usage behavior and the

resulting interests. Furthermore, advertising can also be placed to this effect on the basis of

supposed interests. For this purpose, cookies are usually stored on your end device.

We therefore expressly draw your attention to the fact that the personal data of users (e.g. the

IP address) is stored by the providers of the networks in accordance with their data usage

guidelines and used for business purposes. We would also like to point out that your data may

be processed by these providers outside the European Union or the European Economic Area.

We process the data of users in Konica Minolta's presences on the corresponding social networks

only insofar as they contact and communicate with us via comments or direct messages. You

can assert your rights as a data subject both against us (see also section 2 "What are my rights

as a data subject?") and against the provider of the social network. You can find information on

the processing of your personal data by the individual social network providers as well as the

options for objecting to this under section "9.6.2 Possibilities of objection in social networks" of

this Privacy Policy.

The processing of users' personal data is based on our legitimate interests in effective

information of users and communication with users in accordance with Art. 6 I 1 lit. f GDPR. If

you are asked by the respective providers to give your consent to data processing, the legal basis

for processing is your consent according to Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR.

18

9.6.2 Possibilities of objection in social networks

For a detailed presentation of the respective processing and the possibilities to object (opt-out)

to the data processings by the social networks, we refer to the information of the providers.

In addition, European marketing providers offer a new possibility of objection under the

following link: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/. This is an initiative to educate about online

advertising. In the “Your ad choices” section on YourOnlineChoices.eu - Your ad choices you will

find an overview of providers whose online advertising can be deactivated or activated there.

Also in the case of access requests and the assertion of further rights of data subjects, we would

like to point out that these can most effectively be asserted with the providers. Only the providers

have access to the personal data of the users and can directly take appropriate measures and

provide information. Should you nevertheless require assistance, you can contact us.

9.7 Processing activity – Targeting und Advertisement

9.7.1 Google Adwords

On our website we use the service Google Adwords from Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House,

Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (hereinafter: Google). This service enables us to draw attention

to our appealing offers on external websites by means of advertising material (so-called Google

Ads). These advertising materials are delivered by Google via so-called "Ad Servers". Ad server

cookies are used for this purpose. For further information on the topic of cookies, please go to

"7. cookies". Ad server cookies enable the evaluation of performance parameters (e.g. ad

impressions, clicks or conversions). In this way we can determine how successful the individual

advertising measures are. If you come to our website via an ad from Google, Google Adwords

stores a cookie on your end device. This cookie stores analysis values (unique cookie ID, number

of ad impressions per placement (frequency), last impression, opt-out information (marking that

the user no longer wants to be addressed)). The cookies set by Google Adwords lose their validity

after 30 days. These cookies are not intended to identify you personally. Rather, they enable

Google Adwords to recognize your internet browser. If you visit certain pages on the website of

an Adwords client, Google and the client will recognize that you have been redirected to the

client's page via a clicked advertisement. Google provides us as an Adwords customer with a

statistical analysis. This analysis enables us to measure the effectiveness of our advertising

measures. We do not receive any further data beyond this.

19

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the context of the use of Google

Adwords is your consent according to Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR. When the information stored in the

ad server cookies is transferred to Google's servers. Due to Google's localization, the transfer of

your personal data to Google may involve a third country transfer, i.e. a transfer of personal data

to a destination that is neither in the European Union nor in the European Economic Area, in this

case especially to the USA.

The processing of your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according

to Art. 49 I lit. a GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in

place. As a result, the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights

and freedoms of data subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to

be exercised. Information on your right of withdrawal can be found under section 2.8 "Right of

withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR)" in this privacy policy.

Further information on data protection at Google can be found here:

Privacy Policy – Privacy \& Terms – Google

GDPR \& Google Ads FAQ - Google Ads

9.7.2 LinkedIn Insight Tag

On our website we have included the conversion tool "LinkedIn Insight Tag" from the LinkedIn

Ireland Unlimited Company (hereinafter: LinkedIn).

The LinkedIn Insight Tag is a small JavaScript code snippet that we have implemented on our

website. With the help of the LinkedIn Insight tag, data about the visit of our website is collected

and transmitted to LinkedIn. This data includes the referrer URL, IP address, device information,

browser information, and a timestamp for the visit of our website. LinkedIn does not provide us

with access to the personal data collected in detail. LinkedIn uses this information to provide us

with reports on website audiences and ad performance, based on aggregate data, so that we can

optimize our website based on the information we receive. In addition, LinkedIn provides us with

the ability to track conversions and retarget our website visitors through the LinkedIn Insight

tag. This allows us to display targeted advertising outside of our website without identifying the

website visitor. The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the context of the use

of LinkedIn is your consent pursuant to Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR.

Because of LinkedIn's localization, the transfer of your personal data to LinkedIn may involve a

transfer of personal data to a third country, which is neither in the European Union nor the

European Economic Area, in this case especially to the USA.

20

The processing of your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according

to Art. 49 I lit. a GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in

place. As a result, the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights

and freedoms of data subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to

be exercised. Information on your right of withdrawal can be found under section 2.8 "Right of

withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR)" in this privacy policy.

The data processed in the LinkedIn Insight tag is encrypted and anonymized within seven days.

After 90 days at the latest, the anonymized data is automatically deleted if it is no longer required

for the fulfillment of the defined purpose.

For more information about LinkedIn's privacy policy, please visit the following address:

https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy

9.7.3 MailChimp

We use the services of MailChimp for customer communication and sending newsletters. The

provider is Rocket Science Group LLC, 675 Ponce De Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308,

USA.

MailChimp is a service with which, among other things, the sending of newsletters can be

organized and analyzed. If you enter data for the purpose of receiving newsletters (e.g. e-mail

address), this data will be stored on MailChimp's servers in the USA.

With the help of MailChimp, we can analyze our newsletter campaigns. When you open one of

our emails, a file contained in the email (so-called web beacon) connects to MailChimp's servers

in the USA. This makes it possible to determine whether a newsletter message has been opened

and which links, if any, have been clicked. In addition, technical information is recorded (e.g.

time of retrieval, IP address, browser type and operating system). This information cannot be

assigned to the respective newsletter recipient. It is used exclusively for the statistical analysis

of newsletter campaigns. The results of these analyses can be used to better adapt future

newsletters to the interests of the recipients.

If you do not want any analysis by MailChimp, you have to unsubscribe from the newsletter. For

this purpose, we provide a corresponding link in every newsletter message. Furthermore, you

can also unsubscribe from the newsletter directly on the website.

The data processing is based on your consent (Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR). You can revoke this consent

at any time by unsubscribing from the newsletter. The legality of the data processing operations

already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation.

21

Due to MailChimps server localization, the transfer of your personal data to MailChimp may

involve a third country transfer, i.e. a transfer of personal data to a destination that is neither in

the European Union nor in the European Economic Area, in this case especially to the USA.

The processing of your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according

to Art. 49 I lit. a GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in

place. As a result, the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights

and freedoms of data subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to

be exercised. Information on your right of withdrawal can be found under section 2.8 "Right of

withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR)" in this privacy policy.

9.7.4 Newsletter

Konica Minolta offers newsletters to customers and interested parties on a consent-based

approach. The only mandatory data for receiving the newsletter is your e-mail address. The

provision of further, separately marked data is voluntary and will be used to address you

personally. Registration for the newsletter takes place by means of the so-called double opt-in

procedure. This means that after your registration, we will send you an e-mail to the e-mail

address you provided, in which we ask you to confirm that you wish to receive the information.

If you do not confirm your registration by clicking on the link provided in the e-mail, the link

sent to you will be deactivated and your data will be deleted. If you agree to receive information,

we will send you information about the Aire Link solution.

As part of the double opt-in process carried out during registration, we store the IP addresses

you use for a period of 30 days as well as the times of registration and confirmation. Based on

your consent, we will evaluate your user behavior on our websites as well as within the

newsletters which we send out and assign them to your e-mail address / user profile within our

database. In addition, we store information about the browser you use and the settings made in

your operating system as well as information about your Internet connection with which you have

accessed our website. Via the newsletter sent to you, we receive, among other things, receipt

and read confirmations as well as information about the links you have clicked on in our

newsletter. We also store which areas you have visited on our website and in our apps. By creating

a personal user profile, we want to tailor our advertising approach to your interests and optimize

our offers on our website for you. The data you provide us with for the purpose of receiving the

newsletter will be stored by us until you unsubscribe from the newsletter and will be completely

deleted after you unsubscribe from the newsletter. Data that has been stored by us for other

purposes (e.g. e-mail addresses for the member area) remains unaffected by this.

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data for the above-mentioned purposes is

your consent pursuant to Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR. Your consent can be withdrawn at any time

22

without giving reasons. The withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of the

processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the withdrawal. For more information

about your right of withdrawal, please see section 2.8 "Right of withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR)" in this

privacy policy.

9.8 Processing activity – Youtube

On our websites we have integrated YouTube videos. These are stored at www.youtube.com, but

can be played directly from our website. YouTube is a platform of Google LLC, 1600

Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (hereinafter: Google). We have activated

the enhanced privacy mode when embedding the videos on our website. This means that no

information about you will be sent to YouTube if you do not play the videos. However, when you

play videos, data is transferred to YouTube. First, YouTube is notified that you have visited the

appropriate subpage of our website where the video is embedded. In addition, other data may

be transferred to YouTube that we are not aware of. We also have no influence on the data

transfer. If you are registered on YouTube, the transferred data is directly associated with your

account. YouTube stores your data as usage profiles and uses them for the purpose of

advertising, market research and/or the needs-based design of the website. Such an evaluation

can be carried out in particular (even for users who are not logged in) for the purpose of providing

need-based advertising. You have the right to object to the creation of usage profiles by YouTube

in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR, which you must assert directly with YouTube. The legal basis

for the processing of your personal data in the context of the use of YouTube, which is initialized

by playing a YouTube video, is your consent in accordance with Art. 6 I 1 lit. a GDPR. Further

information on the purpose and scope of data collection and processing can be found in the

YouTube privacy policy.

Youtube is a subsidiary of Google LLC. Due to Google's localization, the transfer of your personal

data to Google may involve a third country transfer, i.e. a transfer of personal data to a

destination that is neither in the European Union nor in the European Economic Area, in this case

especially to the USA.

The processing of your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according

to Art. 49 I lit. a GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in

place. As a result, the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights

and freedoms of data subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to

be exercised. Information on your right of withdrawal can be found under section 2.8 "Right of

withdrawal (Art. 7 GDPR)" in this privacy policy.

23

9.9 Processing activity - Cloudfront

This website uses the content delivery network (CDN) Cloudfront. This is a service of Amazon

Web Services Inc., 410 Terry Avenue North, Seattle, WA 98109-5210 (hereinafter: Amazon Web

Services). The CDN is integrated in the form of Java script code on our website and reloaded

during a visit. Cloudfront allows us to provide increased loading performance, improved

availability and data loss prevention by providing duplicate data (e.g. graphics or scripts) from

this website on different servers around the world. However, when you visit this website,

photo/video files may be automatically requested from Cloudfront, and this automated request

for photo/video files may result in personal data, such as your IP address, being transmitted to

servers of Amazon Web Services. Because of Amazon’s localization, the transfer of your personal

data to Amazon may involve a transfer of personal data to a third country, which is neither in

the European Union nor the European Economic Area, in this case especially to the USA. The

processing of your personal data outside the EU/EEA will be based on your consent according to

Art. 49 I lit. a GDPR. In the USA no guarantees for an adequate data protection level are in place.

As a result, the processing of personal data is affected by additional risks to the rights and

freedoms of data subjects. Rights of data subjects might, in the worst case, not be able to be

exercised.

Due to the fact that Cloudfront is embedded on our website by means of Java Script, you can

prevent its execution by disabling Java Script in your browser or by installing a so-called Java

Script blocker (e.g. https://www.ghostery.com).

The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the context of the use of Cloudfront

is our legitimate interest, which in this case is to ensure the security and availability of this

website, according to Art. 6 I 1 lit. f GDPR.

You can obtain further information on the subject of data protection at Amazon Web Services at

the following address(es): Data Privacy - Amazon Web Services (AWS) or GDPR - Amazon Web

Services (AWS)

10 Konica Minolta Global Policy

To the Global Personal Data Protection Policy
